

Profile

Hello! My name is Ken Joel Gichuhi Muigai and I am a software developer working on web and mobile applications. I have been developing professionally for two years but tinkering with tech since I was a kid. I started tech with open source collaborations, freelance services and individual projects 3 years back.

I have a bit of a diverse job history. I have held a position as a customer service representative, fronted web designer, full stack web developer working on freelance projects and currently I am a Software Developer Intern at MyChoiceTv Limited. I can help everywhere in the stack and I love wearing multiples hats to an extent. Although, I'm certain my strongest skills are in Software Engineering.

The most of my positions utilized agile-like development using Trello, Jenkins and occasionally TFS. I am also a certified scrum master with GitHub. A day in my life consist of adding new features to my fronted projects, creating API endpoints and constantly trying to up skill myself to achieve my long term goal.

Employment History

Software Developer Intern at MyChoiceTV Limited, Nairobi

November 2020 — January 2021

☐ Providing technical support across the company while responding in a timely manner to service issues and requests.

Provide overall administrative support to the organization's systems.

Enhance office IT system through appropriate upgrades and advise
Operations Unit on changes or improvements required.

I Troubleshoot and repair of Software applications.

Customer Service Agent at Startimes Media

November 2019 - March 2020

I was responsible for handling client complains, handling client transactions and giving directives on changes made in the company. I was able to form cohesive interactions that greatly improved my interpersonal relations.

Freelancer, Nairobi

December 2018 — July 2019

Being a self taught web and app developer, I was able to secure remote projects for which I ultimately made deliveries to different clients and within their suited deadlines. I was introduced to agile development using Trello and version control environments such as GitHub. This improved my skills in agile development and continuous integration development. My first freelance project required me to use HTML, CSS and JavaScript to bring to life a simple a simple registration web application. Solving bugs on the project was never quite easy, however

Details

3989, Nairobi Nairobi, 001 Kenya 0792213099 jrjoemuigai@gmail.com

Date of birth 04/03/1998

Nationality Kenyan

Links

Github LinkedIn Website

Skills

Frontend Development

Backend Development

Database Management

Hobbies

Tinkering with natureListening to music

Learning new code and content

Watching movies and documentaries

Languages

English

after much extensive research I was able to solve it and deliver. This was when I fell in love with software development in general and gained the confidence I needed to kick start my career.

Supervisor at Gamers Lounge, Nairobi

January 2017 — January 2018

I was responsible for running a play area in Nairobi. My duties included ensuring the company equipments were maintained as up to date. I was also actively involved in handling client transactions on a day to day basis

Education

Software Development, Moringa School, Nairobi

June 2020 — November 2020

Focused Training on:

Java Development

Android Application Development

Web Development JavaScript and Angular

API Development, Python and Django Framework

Software Development, KCA University, Nairobi

February 2016 — October 2016

I attended was able to grasp what I could throughout my year in school. Even though I was among the unfortunate students who did not manage to complete the course due to funds, I have been able to pick myself up and learn and earn and grow to an outstanding software developer.

Computer Driving License, Elink Collage, Nairobi

November 2015 — January 2016

I attended the three month boot camp where I was taught the basics of computer, mobile devices and software in general.

High School Diploma, JOMO KENYATTA , Nakuru

February 2012 — November 2015

Underwent the school curriculum for 4 years and was able to score an average grade and earn the diploma. Aside from that, I was able to gain the discipline that has helped me since then and will stay with me for the rest of my life.

Extra-curricular activities

Guitar Lessons, Nairobi

March 2019 — March 2020

I mainly attend guitar lessons when I can. Learning the instrument helps me alot.

■ References

Joseph Chagwaya from Startimes Media

chagwayajoseph@gmail.com · 0729002037

Brian Waweru from MyChoiceTv limited

mctvdev@gmail.com · 0759296913

Courses

Web and Android Development, Moringa School of Technology

June 2020 — November 2020

Business Analytics, Udemy

December 2020 — January 2021